<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"><channel><title>Posts on QQrptpooe</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on QQrptpooe</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:32:28 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Good and the Bad of Christian Fundamentalism</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/85708222-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Mar 2024 00:32:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/85708222-the-good-and-the-bad-of-christian-fundamentalism/</guid><description>Fundamentalist beliefs are often regarded as being extreme, restrictive, and even harmful. However, there is a common misconception about Christian fundamentalism that can be harmful to people’s faith journeys. While there are certainly elements of fundamentalist belief systems that can be harmful, such as gender roles, shaming others for their beliefs or lack thereof, and othering those who don’t align with a specific belief system, fundamentalism can also be used to empower people in their own faith journeys.</description></item><item><title>Guilt and the Great Deception in the Christian Life</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/32524613-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 14:40:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/32524613-guilt-and-the-great-deception-in-the-christian-life/</guid><description>What is guilt? How does it impact our lives? And how can we overcome it in our Christian life? These questions will be explored further in this article. When it comes to guilt, we all have to ask ourselves these questions. Everyone feels guilty at times, but only Christians can feel guilty about what Jesus has done for us. Only a true believer has the kind of guilt that causes them to turn from their sinful ways.</description></item><item><title>Why the Church Should Take Responsibility for Its Liberties and Freedoms</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/91214091-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</link><pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 15:57:48 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/91214091-why-the-church-should-take-responsibility-for-its-liberties-and-freedoms/</guid><description>When I talk with pastors about the legal, liability and financial challenges facing their churches in today’s increasingly litigious environment, they often ask, “But we do everything to the best of our ability. As long as that is true, why should anyone try to sue us?” The answer to this question may be the most important reason why churches need liability insurance.
The issue is whether or not to take responsibility for the actions of the individual members of the congregation who are acting on behalf of the church, knowing that the members are probably also covered by some type of personal insurance such as homeowners or car insurance.</description></item><item><title>4 Keys to Building Confidence in God When Life Falls Apart</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/27759116-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 18:42:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/27759116-4-keys-to-building-confidence-in-god-when-life-falls-apart/</guid><description>Today I want to continue what we started on Friday. In that article, I addressed the fact that we are tempted to look at the disappointments, failures, and hardships of our lives and lose confidence in our hope that God has a better way for us to live as His people (see also: Hebrews 11:13-16). But that’s not the way we should think and act, especially when our lives fall apart.</description></item><item><title>Why Christians Can Be Bad at Being Kind</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/28695883-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 14:55:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/28695883-why-christians-can-be-bad-at-being-kind/</guid><description>I grew up with the idea that kindness was the most important. I still believe that kind people make a better world, but I’ve also learned that the emphasis on kindness above all other traits can lead to a handful of problems that are endemic in the church.
Types of Kindness in Christianity There are two main ideas of kindness in Christianity: The virtue of love (which I will refer to as “Goodness” from here-in) and the sacrificial love of God/Jesus (which I will refer to as “Sacrifice” from here-in).</description></item><item><title>Why Are There So Many Ideas about Heaven That Are Not Biblical?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/87546824-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 15:30:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/87546824-why-are-there-so-many-ideas-about-heaven-that-are-not-biblical/</guid><description>Think of heaven as you’d like it to be, then think again. What will your idea of heaven and life after death look like 100 years from now? Will people understand the Biblical message on what heaven and life after death are today? Will humanity have moved on by then? Will it even matter?
The Nature of God Genesis 1:26-27 “Then God said, ‘Let us make man in our image, after our likeness.</description></item><item><title>Why People Are Losing Their Religion (and How the Church Can Respond)</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/22966453-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Mar 2024 15:46:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/22966453-why-people-are-losing-their-religion-and-how-the-church-can-respond/</guid><description>In the last four decades, the United States has seen a dramatic decline in the number of Americans who claim to be affiliated with a Christian church. In 1972, 65% of respondents to a nationwide Gallup Poll identified themselves as belonging to a church or synagogue. By 1998, only 40% did and by 2010, only 38%.^{1} This is not simply due to an increase in the numbers of people who claim no religious affiliation.</description></item><item><title>Why Pastors Struggle to Ask for Help (And How to Get Past It)</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/27716202-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 18:09:17 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/27716202-why-pastors-struggle-to-ask-for-help-and-how-to-get-past-it/</guid><description>Asking for help is one of the most difficult things in life. No one wants to be known as “the weak one.” We want to be strong, self-sufficient, and able to handle whatever comes our way. And being pastors adds its own layers of pressure. As a result, it’s not uncommon for pastors to struggle with asking for help.
As difficult as it might be, however, learning to ask for help can make you stronger and more effective in your role.</description></item><item><title>Why Should Christians Evaluate What Their Lives Are Built On?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/99950393-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2024 10:02:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/99950393-why-should-christians-evaluate-what-their-lives-are-built-on/</guid><description>“Everyone’s building a house!” wrote Dillon Burroughs in one of his books about spiritual growth. “Each is trying to build a life based on something, anything.” Whether it is our jobs, relationships, family, money, possessions, hobbies, sports, entertainment, or something else, he continues, there will always be some foundation that we rely on and try to make a life-plan from. In Matthew 7:24–27 (English Standard Version), Jesus tells this story:</description></item><item><title>Why Do Christians Emphasize Hell Instead of Not Being with God in Heaven?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/77699846-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:14:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/77699846-why-do-christians-emphasize-hell-instead-of-not-being-with-god-in-heaven/</guid><description>Some non-Christians think that it is a bit strange for some Christians to focus on the notion of hell. They wonder why some Christians emphasize hell and eternal punishment in the afterlife instead of the idea of not being with God for eternity. This essay will explain what bothers such non-Christian about Christians emphasizing hell, as well as how the latter could point to a moral issue in the former.</description></item><item><title>How Should Christians Approach Progress in Technology?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/17826885-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Mar 2024 10:06:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/17826885-how-should-christians-approach-progress-in-technology/</guid><description>Technology is a huge deal. It’s everywhere, it’s ubiquitous – it seems to be present and all pervasive across all sectors of society. We can see its impact on our lives, even the most remote of people on earth. Everyday we are using technology to communicate with each other, to go about our daily work or studies and yes for entertainment purposes as well. Here at Frequo, we have noticed how technology continues to transform, change and enhance the workplace.</description></item><item><title>What Does Jesus Teach Us about God's End-Times Plan?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/84248874-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 14:24:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/84248874-what-does-jesus-teach-us-about-god-s-end-times-plan/</guid><description>“Let those who have ears, hear what the Spirit says to the churches” (Rev. 2:29, NIV).
These words are spoken by the exalted Jesus from heaven to the seven churches of Asia. They tell us that those who truly belong to Christ will hearken to His words. But what are they to hear? What are the important lessons the Spirit of God would teach these churches? We find it very difficult to understand this book, for it is symbolic, and must be interpreted according to its literary form.</description></item><item><title>One Key Reason Why Church Consultations Fail</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/30259268-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 2024 14:25:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/30259268-one-key-reason-why-church-consultations-fail/</guid><description>I am an expert on church revitalization. I have written books, produced online content, consulted with 100s of churches worldwide and traveled to hundreds of churches giving workshops and seminars for church renewal. My team of 5 people in the last 21 years have revitalized 9 churches and we are currently working with a number of struggling churches that will be revitalized. If anyone has seen or learned anything about revitalization I think it is us.</description></item><item><title>Is it My Responsibility to Help the Widows and Orphans?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/47912834-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Feb 2024 05:37:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/47912834-is-it-my-responsibility-to-help-the-widows-and-orphans/</guid><description>Is it my responsibility to help widows and orphans? If your answer is yes, you’re in good company. Scripture instructs us to help those in need, including widows and orphans. However, there is a trap in this answer; when helping others, we’re often motivated by our desire for approval more than by a genuine concern for another person’s well-being. We can’t allow our compassion for God’s people to turn into a way to make ourselves feel better.</description></item><item><title>How to Actually Treat Other Believers Like Family</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/78362380-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Feb 2024 19:18:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/78362380-how-to-actually-treat-other-believers-like-family/</guid><description>Welcome to the third episode in this series on The Difference Jesus Makes. In this sermon we will examine the second way that believers in Jesus Christ are to live differently than those who do not follow him. How are Christians to treat other Christians as members of a new family?
I’m hoping you are becoming a little bit more discouraged over the present condition of the church in America. I hope the severe contrast between how American Christians and non-Christians behave and live is clear to you by now.</description></item><item><title>Self-Care: Selfish Habit or Holy Endeavor?</title><link>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/62282921-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 19:01:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://qqrptpooe.github.io/posts/62282921-self-care-selfish-habit-or-holy-endeavor/</guid><description>As the hot summer sun began to set over Michigan and I peered through my back door window, I saw that the grassy field in our front yard had a new, unexplained indentation. Curious, I walked out to the driveway, where an elderly neighbor had stopped me to discuss the local gang problem and other neighborhood issues. A story soon unravelled: what looked like an indentation was actually a child’s body that was discovered after 2 days of disappearance by her grieving mother; she had been kidnapped (babysitting) by gang members and eventually strangled with their shoelaces.</description></item></channel></rss>